Akindele Ridwanullah Akinpelu

Ridwanakindele6@gmail.com, +2347017163895 Frontend Software Engineer

SUMMARY

Akindele is a skilled, consistent and professional Frontend Software Engineer with professional knowledge of maintaining, organizing, implementing and developing information systems and software for human resource, and financial operations. Has experience of customer service in a high-tech environment. Possess a good team spirit, deadline orientated and has the ability to organize and present complex solutions clearly and accurately.

SKILLS

React_Js
 Version Control (Microsoft
 React Native
 Azure, GitHub, Bit Bucket,
 HTML Node Js
 AWS)
 CSS

- TypeScript - RESTful API

- State Management (Redux)

EDUCATION

2023 Bachelor of Science in Microbiology

*****CERTIFICATIONS

2022 ReactJS – Complete guide for frontend developer 2023 The Complete ReactJs Course –Basic to Advance. Till date - National Youth Service Corps (NYSC) Discharge Certificate 2022 Complete Responsive Web Development Course –Basic to Advance

EMPLOYMENT

2022 – 2023 Bonafide 2023 Mystique

LANGUAGES

- English (Full professional proficiency)
- Yoruba (Native Language)

EXPERIENCE

Front-end Software Engineer • Mystique • Jan. 2023 – till date Responsibilities:

- Developing new user-facing features using React.js and React native for both Mobile and web application
- Building reusable components and front-end libraries for future use
- Translating designs and wireframes into high quality code
- Optimizing components for maximum performance across a vast array of webcapable devices and browsers

- Building pixel-perfect, buttery smooth UIs across both mobile platforms.
- Leveraging native APIs for deep integrations with both platforms.
- Diagnose and fix bugs and performance bottlenecks for performance that feels native.
- Maintain code and write automated tests to ensure the product is of the highest quality.
- Transition existing React web apps to React Native.

Methods and Tools used:

AWS, JavaScript, Node Js, React Js, GitHub, Material UI, React icon, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, NPM, Redux, Swagger Documentation, Postman, Visual Studio Code, Slack, OneDrive, Google Meets, Figma, Jira.

Front-end Software Engineer • Bonafide • May. 2022 – 2023 Responsibilities:

- Implementing and developing the User interface using Next.js, Ant-Design, bootstrap
- Consuming Restful API for the service call on pages to interact with the server for information
- Translating designs and wireframes into high quality code
- Optimizing components for maximum performance across a vast array of webcapable devices and browsers
- Writing clean, reusable and scalable code use for business logic
- Building pixel-perfect, buttery smooth UIs.
- Diagnose and fix bugs and performance bottlenecks for performance that feels native.
- Maintain code and write automated tests to ensure the product is of the highest quality.

Methods and Tools used:

JavaScript, Next js, TypeScript, Microsoft Azure, Ant-Design , HTML, CSS, redux Swagger Documentation, Visual Studio Code, Figma, Microsoft Teams, .

★ COMPETENCE

React Js ★★★★

Node Js ★★★
Types cript ★★★
Redux ★★★

AWS ★

Microsoft Azure **

JavaScript **

RESTful API **

HTML **

CSS **

GitHub

* ** *** *** Some Basic Knowledge Basic Knowledge Good Knowledge Very Good Knowledge

Experts